[Music]
your commentator is Joel Bryant here is
the motion picture record released by
the United States Navy of the havoc
wrought by the Japs sneak sky and sea
raid on Pearl Harbor
America's mid Pacific Naval bastion on
December 7th 1941 Japan like its
infamous axis partners struck first and
declared war afterwards costly to our
Navy was the loss of war vessels
airplanes and equipment but more costly
to Japan was the effectiveness of its
foul attack in immediately unifying
America in its determination to fight
and win the war thrust upon it and to
win the peace that will follow the Japs
copied their German masters in striking
hard at airfields Hickam Field northwest
of Honolulu and the Ford Island naval
plane base were the first objectives of
Japan's treachery scores of planes were
bruised and battered by the Japs aerial
bombs many of these were demolished
beyond repair direct hits were scored on
hangers and these were badly shattered
equipment and airplane supplies were
reduced to smoldering ruins here at the
Naval Air Station is grim and positive
evidence of [ __ ] treachery here fall
blows were struck while [ __ ] diplomats
were talking peace in Washington
America lost three destroyers here are
seen the United States destroyers downs
and Shore as they rest on the bottom of
Pearl Harbor with decks awash after [ __ ]
bombers make direct hits on their decks
first to feel the sting of Japanese
steel are the USS Oklahoma and Utah the
latter a 33 year old target ship
accurate hits by the enemy bombers make
short work of these two naval bulwarks
now with their keels practically out of
water they lie helpless wrecks and a sad
reminder of cowardly strategy to make
possible a surprise attack within Pearl
Harbor the Japs built two-man submarines
to enable them to fire sneak blows
within waters that are narrow and
tortuous several of these surprise
weapons were blown from the water by
direct hits of our naval Gunners others
were beached and captured while sky and
sea fire was still raging salvage crews
inspected our naval craft to estimate
what may be saved
before the denver's ting bombs had been
silenced preparations were underway to
salvage these two warships at low tide
the huge propeller of the Oklahoma
stilled by the enemy was high above
water it is believed that the small
two-man [ __ ] submarines carrying dual
torpedo tubes were responsible for these
two losses to our Pacific Fleet
[Music]
here is the actual bombing of the mighty
USS arizona by [ __ ] planes these pictures
were made by a fearless cameraman who
thought nothing of his personal safety
to make possible this record for all
posterity a single lucky hit was
responsible for the disaster that befell
the Arizona when a [ __ ] bomb falling
directly through one of the battleships
funnels exploded in the engine room and
set ablaze tons of fuel oil dense black
smoke billowed to the sky as the massive
control tower began to keel over the
Arizona's courageous crew stuck to its
guns until the very end here was
displayed heroism that will live forever
in the glorious annals and traditions of
the American Navy
[Music]
the once-mighty Arizona now rests on
pearl harbors muddy bottom a pitiful
relic of its former self
a grim monument to the treachery of
Japan the once mighty dreadnaughts armor
plate is twisted and torn but the great
battleships control tower still stands a
defiant beacon that in days to come will
cast its shadow upon nippon x' very
Shores at Pearl Harbor at Hickam Field
in the bomb pop streets of Honolulu ever
is written history history with a tragic
treacherous pen history that 130 million
Americans will never forget and in days
to come
the Japs too will remember Pearl Harbor
here is a tragic unforgettable page in
the annals of America here the cunning
deceit of the Japs will never be
forgotten
here they hope to score a knockout
before the war began the Arizona's gun
crews battered and broken fire to the
last their guns pointed skyward from
whence the enemy appear the Japs sneak
blow caused hundreds of military and
civilian lives the treacherous attack
cost our Pacific Fleet two battleships
outright another capsized the loss of
three destroyers and a mine layer
[Music]
while bombs were still bursting and
flames still pouring from our shattered
naval craft a light United States
Cruiser valiantly moves out to join the
fleet and avenge Pearl Harbor